So let's now look at some attacks that you may encounter.
We always talk about how hackers take over our accounts and sell viruses on our computers.
But a question that nobody ever asks is like, how does the hacker manage to reach me?
Let's try to answer that question today.
We will then talk about attacks involving site cloning, spam, adware, keylogger, WiFi hacker and
Google hacking.
In addition, we will see leaked databases in how to check if our emails have been leaked on the internet
and if they come with passwords that we use.
And we will also see phishing emails.
Don't worry if you didn't understand, we will move forward little by little to understand each detail.