Fig pages, a clone of a site or a fake page is simply a copy of the main login page of a famous and
normal site to be placed on a fake URL and to see victims.
There are two types of this attack.
There is the attack of clone sites on land where the hacker needs to be on the same network as the victim.
And there is the clone of sites on typosquatting links that are malicious URLs that can reach the victim
through emails.
Clone sites on land.
When the attacker clones sites on land, he needs to have access to the user's network.
For this, he can use, for example, a Wi-Fi network from the user's home, the Wi-Fi Anthony Network.
If someone discovers the password and connects to the network, he will be on a network of devices.
The notebook or computer will be together with the devices of all the people who are connected to that
network.
And when connecting the router sends this new user an IP number that is nothing more than a number to
locate the device on that network.
IP address.
There are two types of IP address.
There is the client IP address that will request files and there is the server IP address that will
respond to client requests by sending the files that the client requested.
Client IP.
For example, if the user 192.168 1.7 entered his browser and requested pages from Facebook, the browser
then contacts Facebook, which has this server IP and requests the files from the server.
Facebook's server then sends the files for the user to see.
So all users on a common local network, a Wi-Fi or wired network are clients.
They only receive the pages and files they request.
Server IP.
An attacker can turn his client IP into a server so the same user who has the IP 1.7 can now also send
files.
So after this user turns his computer into a server on the Wi-Fi.
Anthony Network all users on that network who access the IP 1.7 will receive files from that user's
computer.
And it is in this context that the fake site attack happens.
The sites we see are files with an HAML extension.
The attacker can clone this original site haml file and put a keylogger script behind that page.
This script will record all the keys typed by the user and send them all to the hacker.
So if the attacker puts this Haml file with this script on his computer that is now a server, the people
who access it will have access to this haml file, and if they enter their information, the hacker
will have the email and password shortly thereafter.
But for this attack to work, the victim needs to manually enter this IP in the browser.
And no user would do this because it is not normal.
The hacker could open the page on the user's computer, but for that you would already need to have
access to the same computer.
And if he already has access, he doesn't need to create a fake site.
He just needs to activate the keylogger without needing the clone DNS service.
There is something called DNS.
This service translates a domain to a server.
IP domain is, for example, Google.com, Facebook.com, Amazon.com.
It is an easy name that a person can register with abc.com, BR and other available extensions.
Each server has its respective IP on the internet.
The IP is a unique number that locates the devices and for the user to access these servers, he will
need to memorize the IP number of each server he wants to access.
So to access the Facebook server, he needs to enter the complete IP number of Facebook test entering
Facebook IP.
Do you know how many sites exist on the Internet?
In January 2019, the Internet had 1.9 billion sites.
Now imagine having to learn the IP of all these servers to be able to access the sites.
It would be horrible.
So that the user does not need to memorize these numbers.
There is the DNS service that links a domain to an IP.
So Internet DNS takes Facebook's IP and stores it in the Facebook.com box.
So when a client wants to access Facebook, the browser will communicate with the DNS service requesting
to know which IP to access the Facebook.com server.
DNS will open the box, check the IP that is in the box, give it to the browser and the browser will
send the message to this IP requesting the files.
And finally the server will respond by sending the requested files.
So every site on the internet has its own IP.
Facebook, Google, Amazon, YouTube, Twitter, Wikipedia, AliExpress and etcetera.
DNS Spoof.
There is an attack called DNS Spoof, which consists of changing the IP of an original site and putting
the attacker's IP.
So in a DNS spoof attack on the WiFi Anthony network, there is the Facebook.com domain that redirects
to the Facebook IP.
The attacker doing the DNS spoof would be on the network, manipulating the DNS service to change Facebook's
IP and put his IP in its place.
So now if someone on Anthony's network types Facebook.com in the browser, they will have the Facebook
page.
But when they enter the email and password, the data will be sent to the attacker.
Clone sites with Typosquatting.
The second type of attack is the clone of sites with their own domains where the attacker creates a
URL similar to the original and puts the clone files inside it.
This is called Typosquatting.
Typosquatting is a URL hijacking attack that takes advantage of URL.
Misspellings.
Where a hacker can create clone sites of the original and gain information from users who end up falling
into these URLs.
For example, a person who will type Google.com with two O's and types Google.com with three O's.
Typosquatting levels orthographic error replacing a with e addition of character putting ins different
extension in case you didn't know.com and.com.org or org or any other extension are completely different
websites and people who don't know this are at serious risk of being ripped off.
Phishing subdomain put a sub.
Domain to try to impersonate a company in a rural that does not belong to the company.
Group sites use hyphen in the URLs to also try to trick people impersonating a company.
Orthographic errors.
In addition to typing errors, the URL Hijacking Attack also uses characters that look like others to
form a URL.
This attack is called a Homographic attack replaced I with a replace him with ERN.
It may be that someone might report that they noticed that Vern is not a gnome.
However, when we quickly look over the URL, we can actually confuse the ERN and see an in its place
and end up clicking and falling for a scam.
This is very powerful in email inboxes where no one pays attention to these details.
Misspelling.
There are cases where misspelling can also be used for marketing, and it is called misspelling.
There are several companies that have grown because they use spelling errors in their competitor's domains
to redirect customers to their site.
For example, Verizon, Lufthansa and in 2016, an evangelical named Jerry Falwell attempted to sue
to own a domain that was imitating his blog and spreading hate against homosexuals.
His site was falwell.com and the fake site was falwell.com with two URLs.
However, he did not win the case and the guy who spread hate continued with the domain.
Lego paid over $500,000 in cases of typosquatting domains.
There were over 309 cases of domains pretending to be Lego.
Google has more than 32 domains registered with spelling errors in the word Google, because in 2011,
the domain with two guys was registered and it was a fishing site.
Google managed to take down this site, and after that they did research and bought several domains
with spelling errors of their original domain.
Google itself created a page for online site administrators where it explains five reasons to have more
than one domain, and one of the factors is spelling errors.
All major sites today have typosquatting domains to prevent users from falling into phishing scams of
this type, such as Netflix, Amazon and Facebook, which also have domains with spelling errors of
their main domains.